Daniel Levy

Software Engineer

(778) 872-4300

□ daniel.levy789@gmail.com

Richmond, BC, Canada

Objective

My name is Daniel Levy and I have been working at TELUS as a software developer for the last three years as my first job out of university. Over that time, I was able to work with a diverse and knowledgeable team on a variety of projects in the web development and cloud architecture domain. I am looking to apply the knowledge I have learned so far on new and exciting challenges, and continue to develop my skills as a software engineer.

Skills

- Front end development: JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, AngularJS, Redux, Figma
- **Back end development:** Node.js, Python, Express, Fastify, API design
- Cloud architecture: Docker, Kubernetes, GCP, Terraform, OpenShift
- **Soft skills:** Communication, leadership, team work, attention to detail, problem solving, presentations and public speaking
- Project management: Jira, GitHub, Agile methodology, requirement generation, delegation and people management

Work Experience

CLOUD DEVELOPER - ENGINEERING PRODUCTIVITY

TELUS | Vancouver, BC | April 2023 - Present

- Built client applications to enable my colleagues to connect to our enterprise AI models on both Slack and Google
 Chat, and completely redesigned and reimplemented an existing attempt to build a web application for the same
 purpose. Over the first nine months of these applications' existences, we saw over 17,000 unique users and over
 one million requests handled.
- Developed internal Slack applications in Node.js and Python that utilized the power of artificial intelligence to
 make troubleshooting and support documents more accessible while reducing the load on our support team.
- Designed and implemented an internal self reflection application for developers to gain an understanding of their satisfaction levels and overall experience while working at TELUS. Over our three month pilot, we found that developers who regularly reflected on their days were 45% more satisfied overall than our control group.
- Enabled our automation teams to better streamline the employee onboarding process by developing an API that allows for the querying of GitHub usernames with employee ID numbers and vice versa.
- Analyzed and documented the existing process to take an application to production at TELUS in order to unify
 the scattered existing documentation and improve developer experience. Surveyed users reported a reduction in
 the time it took to take an application to production by 14 days on average.

TECHNOLOGY SPECIALIST - GRADUATE TECHNOLOGY LEADERSHIP PROGRAM

TELUS | Vancouver, BC| September 2020 - April 2023

- Collaborated with network planners to develop a new network configuration tool for cell sites using React.js for the front end and Node.js for the back end. Our application replaced a legacy application and we had an 87% satisfaction rate among surveyed planners a month after our production release.
- Managed the refactor of a crucial front door application for field technicians that used AngularJS and PHP for the front end and back end respectively. The implementation was planned by me in Jira and responsibilities were delegated to a co-op student who was working with me, and I was responsible for keeping the leadership team and stakeholders in the loop during development.
- Contributed to migration of over 50 microservices from OpenShift to Google Cloud Platform. All configurations were updated to work in the new infrastructure and deployments and testing of new instances were done after hours to reduce downtime for consumers.
- Developed an internal ticket management tool through all stages of the development lifecycle from requirement
 gathering with key stakeholders, to designing and implementing the UI and API in React.js and Fastify, as well as
 the deployment and maintenance of the running services in OpenShift.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER IN TEST

BuildDirect | Vancouver, BC | January 2018 - August 2018

- Developed and maintained multiple automated end-to-end test suites for an e-commerce platform using Selenium that would run as part of our CICD process in Jenkins.
- Coordinated with multiple development squads to ensure that new tests were able to ensure requirements were met before deployments could be done, and then implemented those changes in a timely manner.
- Documented and triaged issues that would appear in our production site and helped develop rapid fixes to
 prevent loss of revenue from negative customer experience.

Education

University of British Columbia - September 2015 - May 2020

Bachelor of Applied Science - BASc, Computer Engineering

GPA: 3.74 out of 4

Volunteering Initiatives

TECHNICAL ARCHITECT

TELUS Digital Strategy Subprogram | October 2020 - April 2023

- Served as the technical architect for a team of volunteers developing and maintaining an internal site for fellow new graduate program members to find resources and connect with the new graduate community.
- Discussed feasibility of new features with stakeholders and managers and oversaw all major technical decisions and discussions for the site.
- Ran regular team sprint meetings, delegated tasks to team members, and helped unblock developers when they ran into issues with their features.
- Developed new features for the front and back end of the site as well as ensured that our CICD processes were following industry standards in terms of automation, environment management and build optimization.

MENTORING

TELUS Women in STEM Mentorship Program | January 2022 – June 2022

- Participated in a program to provide technical and non-technical mentorship to women starting their careers in a STEM related field.
- Coordinated with mentee and provided two mentoring sessions per month, over a six month period.
- Discussed short term and long term goals with mentee and developed an actionable plan towards achieving those goals in a reasonable time frame.
- Provided career and personal advice to mentee based on my past experiences as well as encouragement to help in their career development.